<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MonthlyInvest</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://monthlyinvest.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://monthlyinvest.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 16:49:28 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 16:49:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basics of Investing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While investing a lumpsum amount is not bad, it is actually the regular savings that helps in accumulating wealth over time.
Slowly and steadily, regular investing becomes a habit that can reward you in future. It provides the discipline to allocate money for saving before you have the temptation to spend it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goal-based-investment&quot;&gt;Goal based Investment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before thinking of investing regularly on a monthly basis, the most important part is to define financial goals. Setting financial goals will give you a rough idea of the amount that should be contributed towards a goal. Some examples of common goals are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To have life protection cover &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To provide adequate cover for child education and child marriage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build Retirement corpus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The type of investment varies by the type of target goal. Some of the example saving instruments are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bank Deposits (FD, RD)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PPF, PF&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insurance policies (Term Plan, ULIP, Pension plans)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mutual Funds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Equities (Stock Market)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common tendency prevalent among most people is to increase their contribution in fixed income instruments like PPF, FD, RD etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let us take an example. There are three persons Ram, Shyam and Ramesh. All of them are 25 years in age and have the same goal to accumulate funds for child’s education. However, each person follows a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ram decided to go for lumpsum saving once very six months. He puts that money in FD, PPF, NSC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shyam decided to invest monthly and put that money in fixed income instruments like RD, PPF&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ramesh decided to invest monthly and put that money in PPF, Equity Mutual fund, Equities, Bullion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now which one of above three is most likely to over-achieve his goal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you agree with Ram/Shyam’s selection, then you are most definitely going to miss on your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;equities-vs-debt&quot;&gt;Equities vs Debt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there is no surety with Ramesh selection as well but there are more than decent chances of achieving the goal with that selection . 
Choosing the correct strategy is half the work done . But Now comes another important part , that is selection of Equity Mutual fund and equities. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://monthlyinvest.com/blog/2014/09/basics-of-investing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://monthlyinvest.com/blog/2014/09/basics-of-investing/</guid>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
        <category>gyan</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
